

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211





Sivarajan R Sivarajan R R Featured Scrum Master seeking roles in Software Development, Application Development, Software Design, Software Testing, Project Management, Change Management, Quality Management, Defect Management, Requirement Gathering, Eclipse, WinSCP, Putty, MySQL, JIRA, PMP, XML, JCL Current Location: Chennai Total Experience: 14 Year(s) 0 Month(s) Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad Notice Period: 15 Days or less Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming / Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computer Science] Maintenance Role: Project Mar-IT/Software Industry: IT-Software/Software Services Marital Status: Married Key Skills: Scrum Master, Project Manager, Software Development, Application Development, Software Design, Software Development Testing, Project Management, Change Management, Quality Management, Defect Management, Requirement Gathering, Eclipse, WinSCP, Putty, MySQL, JIRA, PMP, XML, JCL Verified : Email - id

Important

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

Summary

Last Active: 18-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Total 14 years of experience in Analysis, Design, Development, Testing, and Maintenance of IT projects, which includes extensive experience in B2B projects using WebMethods ,Gentran and Mainframe product suite and WSO2.

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills | Projects

Last Modified: 18-Jan-21

3 yrs of experience as a Scrum Master for software development team, Certified Professional Scrum Master (PSM).

Worked in client location OfficeMax/OfficeDepot, Naperville, USA for 7+ years and 4 years of experience as Onsite Offshore coordinator.

Expert in onsite - offshore implementation model , worked as e-Commerce Analyst, involved in providing strategic direction for all B2B integration points as well as providing support and communication with trading partners B2B IT team and internal business users.

Good experience in WSO2 Enterprise Integrator, WebMethods toolset WebMethods 6.1/6.5/8.2. (WebMethods components such as My WebMethods Server, Trading Networks, and WebMethods adapters such as JDBC, SAP, and WebMethods solutions like WMEDI, WMFlatFile, WMEDIINT etc.

Work Experience

Quinnox as Scrum Master, PMP, PSM Dec 2006 to Apr 2020

Quinnox (Nov 2019 - April 2020)Location: Bangalore

Client/Product: WSO2 Role: Scrum Master

Project Description:

WSO2 is an open-source technology and allows developers to integrate services and applications in an easy, efficient and productive manner. This project is about integrating applications, interfaces which involve different data formats for WSO2 external

customers

Major responsibilities as Scrum Master - ? Build and lead high-performing and self-organizing, cross-functional teams, in order to deliver quality throughput. ? Responsible for protecting the team from outside interference and takes a leadership role in removing impediments or

aiding to remove impediments. ? Formulate the DOR and DOD for the Sprint and Release in consent with the Development team & PO. ? Coach and educate the team to understand the values of Scrum. ? Improve the engineering practices and tools so that each increment of functionality is potentially shippable. ? Interact with leadership team and help with early indicators towards outcomes (Predictability, release frequency, quality).

Quinnox (Oct 2019 - Nov 2019) Location: SriLanka

Client/Product: WSO2

Role: Scrum Master /Senior Consultant

Project Description and responsibilities:

WSO2 product support is to provide L1,L2 and L3 technical support to WSO2 customers. I went to WSO2 Colombo office for knowledge transition for the incident/query created by customers which is in production and non production environments where a failure of a system will impact on the end users and on the organization.

Client: SANY America - Integration of SAP with Sales Force

Role: Scrum Master/ Senior Consultant

Tech Skills: WSO2 Enterprise Integrator 6.4, Salesforce and SAP,JIRA

Project Description:

Enabling integration by developing Interfaces and APIs(for parts orders, machines, warranty claims, Account creation and inspections) for data to flow from/to three different Vendors that is SFDC, SAP and Dealer Portal application using Salesforce and SAP connectors to have seamless transactional data flow among the various systems.

Major responsibilities:

- * Build and lead high-performing and self-organizing, cross-functional teams, in order to deliver quality throughput.
- * Responsible for protecting the team from outside interference and takes a leadership role in removing impediments or aiding to remove impediments.
- Improve the engineering practices and tools so that each increment of functionality is potentially shippable.
- * Helped Development Team for integrations between Salesforce and Dealer portal as per data object provided.
- * Support SANY during User Acceptance Testing Go Live activities and production issues by adhering the SLAs.
- * Train & guide development team, product owner on principles, roles and artifacts ,facilitates daily scrum, sprint planning, sprint demo and retrospective meetings.

Quinnox (Dec 2010 - July 2018) Location: Naperville, US

Client: OfficeDepot/OfficeMax - webMethods EDI B2B Integration

Role: Programmer Analyst

Tech Skills: webMethods integration suite 8.2, Mainframe

Project Description:

OfficeMax/OfficeDepot is a leader in both business-to-business office product solutions and retail office products provides office supplies and paper, technology products and solutions, and furniture to large, medium and small businesses and consumers. Approximately 40,000 associates through direct sales, catalogs, Internet and approximately 900 superstores, serve OfficeMax customers. They use all types of documents for B2B Integration. This project involved Development, Enhancement & Migration to support B2B integration for OfficeMax.

Vista Infotech as Software Engineer

Jun 2006 to Nov 2006

Client: North Western Mutual Life - Benefits and Premium Pages

Role: Software Engineer

Tech Skills: PL/1, JCL, File Manager, Xpediter

Project Description:

North Western Mutual Life was introducing three new universal life Products. They are CVUL (Custom Variable Universal Life), EVUL (Executive Variable Universal Life), SVUL (Sunivorship Variable Universal Life). VEL (Variable Executive Life) and VJL (Variable Joint Life) are existing Products. Contract Package consists of Spec Pages and Benefits and Premium Pages. Additional functionalities will be added to VEL and VJL products as a part of this TTVUL project.

Responsibilities:

- * Involved in doing Initial Business Requirements, Designing, Development & testing.
- Preparing Detailed Level Design documents and Coding
- * Preparing Test Plans, Test Cases
- * Involved in Unit testing

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E (Computer Science) from Manonmaniam Sundaranar University in 2003

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs: Certified Scrum Master WSO2 CERTIFIED ENTERPRISE INTEGRATOR DEVELOPER WSO2 CERTIFIED DEVELOPER Project Management Professional

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
COBOL,JCL,PL/1,CICS,VSAM			
WSO2Enterprise Integrator,webMethods8.2			
Gentran, FileManager, Xpediter,FILE-AID			
PrincetonRelational Changeman			
MySQL			0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
SoapUI, PostMan, Edipse, WinSCP, putty			
XML,CXML, XCBL, OAG, EDI, Flat File,IDOC			

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert	✓	✓	✓
Tamil	Expert	✓	✓	✓
Hindi	Reginner	1		

Projects

Project Title: WSO2

Client: WSO2

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Nov 2019 - Apr 2020 Project Location: Bangalore Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Role: Other Team Size: 6

Skill Used: Scrum, Agile Project Management, Wso2

Role Description: Scrum Master

Project Details: ?Build and lead high-performing and self-organizing, cross-functional teams, in order to deliver quality throughput.

?Responsible for protecting the team from outside interference and takes a leadership role in removing impediments or aiding to remove impediments.

?Formulate the DOR and DOD for the Sprint and Release in consent with the Development team & PO.

?Coach and educate the team to understand the values of Scrum.

?Improve the engineering practices and tools so that each increment of functionality is potentially shippable.

?Interact with leadership team and help with early indicators towards outcomes (Predictability, release frequency, quality).

Project Title: WSO2

Client: WSO2

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Oct 2019 - Nov 2019 Onsite / Offsite: Onsite Project Location: Srilanka Role: Other Team Size: 14

Skill Used: Wso2, Scrum, Agile Project Management

Role Description: Scrum Master

Project Details: WSO2 is an open-source technology and allows developers to integrate services and applications in an easy, efficient and productive manner. This project is about integrating applications, interfaces which involve different data formats for WSO2 customers.

Project Title: SANY America - Integration of SAP with Sales Force

Client: Sany America

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Aug 2018 - Sep 2019 Project Location: Bangalore Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Role: Other Team Size: 9

Skill Used: Wso2, Scrum, Agile Development, SFDC, SAP ABAP

Role Description: Scrum Master
Project Details: ?Facilitating Grooming, Sprint Planning, Stand up, Demo/Review and Retrospective meetings

?Mentoring teams on Agile practices

?Coaching the team on Scrum events and values

?Ensuring a good relationship between the team and product owner as well as others outside the team.

?Enabling teams to identify and resolve impediments

?Identifying and resolving anti patterns

?Support/help the team with agile ways of working

Project Title: OfficeDepot - Merger B2B Integration

Client: Office Depot

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jan 2017 - Jul 2018 Project Location: Napervilla, USA Onsite / Offsite: Onsite Team Size: 18 Role: Module Leader Skill Used: Webmethods, MWS, Trading Networks, Mainframes, Scrum Master

Role Description: Project Coordinator

Project Details: This project involved migrating the existing maps form OfficeMax to OfficeDepot system, also development, enhancement & migration to support B2B integration for OfficeMax. Day to day transactions are happening and end-to-end integration of document from webMethods through MQ Series to Mainframes and SAP is being involved.

Project Title: OfficeMax- webMethods EDI Contract

Client: OfficeMax

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Dec 2010 - Dec 2016 Onsite / Offsite: Onsite Project Location: Naperville, US Role: Sr. Programmer Team Size: 11

Skill Used: Gentran Integration Suite, Mainframes

Role Description: ?Manage client expectations from a timeline and delivery perspective Coordinate with internal and external customers as necessary

?Have managed the Releases by creating the PROD Change Requests and get the required CAB approvals.

?Determine the scope

Project Details: OfficeMaxis a leader in both business-to-business office product solutions and retail office products provides office supplies and paper, technology products and solutions, and furniture to large, medium and small businesses and consumers. Approximately 40,000 associates through direct sales, catalogs, Internet and approximately 900 superstores, serve OfficeMax customers. They use all types of documents for B2B Integration.

Project Title: EDI

Client: OfficeMax

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Dec 2006 - Nov 2010 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: This project is about developing and maintaining EDI maps in Gentran and mainframe setups for connectivity with other applications. Implementing EDI Transactions such as 215,810,812,820,824,830, 832,843,850,855,856,857,860,864,875, 880, 894 and 997.

Project Title: North Western Mutual Life - Benefits and Premium Pages

Client: North Western Mutual Life

Duration: Jun 2006 - Nov 2006 Nature of Employment: Contractual Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Project Location: Bamgalore Role: Programmer Team Size: 10

Skill Used: PL1, Mainframes

Project Details: North Western Mutual Life was introducing three new universal life Products. They are CVUL (Custom Variable Universal Life), EVUL (Execuve Variable Universal Life), SVUL (Survivorship Variable Universal Life). VEL

(Variable Execuve Life) and VJL (Variable Joint Life) are exisng Products. Contract Package consists of Spec Pages and Bene?ts and Premium Pages. Addional funconalies will be added to VEL and VJL products as a part of this TTVUL project.

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.